Guide to the Archives of Irish America Newspapers and Periodicals Collection AIA.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Newspapers, 1836-2020; 211.5 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 4 flat file folders, and 204 oversized boxes
  - The Phoenix (New York), 1859-1861; cuid14753 (Box 185, Reel R-7943)
    Digital access to The Phoenix is available through the University of Missouri Digital Library: http://dl.mospace.umsystem.edu/mu/islandora/object/mu%3A1249
    Custodial History
    The physical copy of The Phoenix in Box 185 was donated to the archives by Sean Prendiville and separated from his personal papers (AIA 005).
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Due to the fragility of the physical copy of this publication, researchers must use either the microfilm or online version before requesting the original.
  - Plain Dealer "PD Action Tab", Mar 1973; cuid14754 (Box 145)
  - San Francisco Gael, Feb 1993–Mar 1994; cuid14755 (Box 145)
  - Saoirse (Irish Freedom)(Dublin), May-Oct 1972, May 1987–Oct 1998, Jan 2005-Jun 2011; cuid14756 (Box 183)
  - Saoirse (Irish Freedom) (Dublin), 1972-2017 (Box 224, Folder 1-7)
    August 1972, March 1997, June 2000, June 2002, July 2005, Sept 2008, Aug-Sept 2011, Nov 2011, Feb-May 2012, Aug-Sept 2012, Nov-Dec 2012, Jan 2013, April-Dec 2013, 2014 (except August), Feb-Dec 2015, 2016, 2017
  - Saoirse (Irish Freedom) (Dublin), 2018, 2019, Jan-Mar 2020 (Box 223, Folder 5-7)
  - Shamrock News, Mar 1976; cuid14757 (Box 145)
  - Shamrock; or, Hibernian Chronicle, 1811; cuid14758 (Box Shared Tamiment 175, Folder 15)
  - South Boston On-Line Print Edition, Jul 2001; cuid14759 (Box 145)
  - Sovereign Nation (Dublin), Oct 1998, Aug 2001, Aug-Sept 2008; cuid14760 (Box 145, Box 220, Folder 5)
  - The Sunday World, Oct 2008 (Box 220, Folder 14)
  - Tablet (Queens and Brooklyn, NY), Mar 1996; cuid14761 (Box 145)
  - Threshold, Sep 1981; cuid14762 (Box 145)
  - Tom Mannion Travel Supplement, Feb 1985; cuid14763 (Box 145)
  - TWU Express, Dec 1963; cuid14764 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), 1955–1961; cuid14765 (Box 149)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), Aug 1971-May 1972; cuid14766 (Box 149)
  - United Irishman (Dublin), Mar 1973 (Box 220, Folder 8)
  - United Literary Supplement, Spring 2006, Fall 2007 (Box 220, Folder 6)
- Series II: Other Periodicals, 1881-2019; 14.49 Linear Feet in 8 record cartons, 14 manuscript boxes, and 3 half manuscript boxes
  The materials in this series consist of various publications including The Nation (published by the Irish American Defense Fund), Spirit of Freedom (an Irish American publication in support of republicanism in Northern Ireland), Irish America (a magazine focusing on the Irish in America and famous Americans of Irish heritage), Ireland of the Welcomes (the official publication of the Ireland Tourist Board) and An Gaodhal (a bi-lingual magazine concerning art, music, and the Irish language).
  - Ais Eiri: The Magazine of Irish-America, 1979-1981; cuid14767 (Box 160, Folder 1A)
  - American Committee for Irish Studies, 1963-1964, 1966-1968, 1970-1979; cuid14768 (Box 160, Folder 1-3)
  - American Gael, 1992-1999; cuid14771 (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - American Irish Newsletter American Irish Political Education Committee, 1993-1999, February 2000-July 2000; cuid14772 (Box 160, Folder 5, 5A, 5B)
  - American Journal of Gaelic Culture (Chicago), 1996-1997; cuid14775 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soulis, Inc. - Newsletter - Litir Nuacht, 1971-1977; cuid14776 (Box 160, Folder 6)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - Sword of Light,The Irish American Review, 1974; cuid14777 (Box 160, Folder 7)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc.- Ais-Eiri The Magazine of Irish America, Win 1979-Spr 1982; cuid14778 (Box 160, Folder 8)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc. - An Gael, 1982-1987, 1990-1992; cuid14779 (Box 160, Folder 9-13)
  - An Doras, 1996-1998; cuid14784 (Box 160, Folder 14)
  - An Gaodhal, 1881, 1886-1891, 1893-1894, 1896-1899, 1900-1902; cuid14785 (Box 166, Folder 10-15, Box 219, Folder 1-2)
  - An Phoblacht, 2019 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Bard, The, 1996-1999; cuid14791 (Box 160, Folder 15)
  - Beyond Ben Bulben (Australia), 1996-1997; cuid14792 (Box 160, Folder 16)
  - Bonded Shores, 1994-2000; cuid14793 (Box 160, Folder 17)
  - The Bridge: An Droichead, 1986-1987; cuid14794 (Box 160, Folder 18)
  - Callahan's Irish Quarterly, 1977-2008; cuid14795 (Box 160, Folder 19-20)
  - Carn: A Link Between Celtic Nations, 1974-1978; cuid14797 (Box 160, Folder 21)
  - Celtic News Service, 1975-1977, 1992-1996; cuid14798 (Box 160, Folder 22)
  - Celtic Renewal, 1995; cuid14799 (Box 160, Folder 23)
  - Cois na Farraige, 1984; cuid14800 (Box 160, Folder 24)
  - Desert Shamrock, 1994; cuid14801 (Box 160, Folder 25)
  - Ducas, 1971-1981 with gaps; cuid14802 (Box 161, Folder 26)
  - Ducas, 1985-2002; cuid14803 (Box 161, Folder 27)
  - Eire Ireland, 1963-1988 (Box 161, Folder 1-2, Box 194, Folder 2-5, Box 195, Folder 1-4, Box 196, Folder 1-5, Box 197)
  - Everyman, 1994-1995; cuid14806 (Box 161, Folder 3)
  - Film Ireland, 1992-2002 (Box 197, Folder 5, Box 198, Folder 1-5, Box 199, Folder 1-3)
  - Gaelic Journal, 1900; cuid14807 (Box 161, Folder 4)
  - Gander, 1993-2002, 2004; cuid14808 (Box 161, Folder 5-7)
  - Harp: "Voice of the Irish Impression", Jun 1988; cuid14811 (Box 161, Folder 8)
  - Here's Me Bus!, 1995-1996; cuid14812 (Box 161, Folder 9)
  - Hibernian Life (Minneapolis, MN): vol. ii, no. 3, Jul-Sep 1989; cuid14813 (Box 166, Folder 16)
  - Holy Cross Quarterl y: The Irish Issue, Vol. 6, Nos. 1-4. College of the Holy Cross, Worcester, MA., 1974; cuid14814 (Box 161, Folder 9A)
  - Hornpipe: Irish Dance, Music and Culture in North America, 1999; cuid14815 (Box 161, Folder 10)
  - I.E.: Supplement to the Irish Echo, 1993, 2000-2001 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Inside Ireland, 1984, 1999; cuid14816 (Box 161, Folder 11)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, Mar 1966-Mar 1978, 1984-2001, May-Jun 2016; cuid14817 (Box 161, Folder 12-19, Box 162, Folder 1-5, Folder 20-23, Box 239, Folder 1)
  - Iris, 2006-2008 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Irish America, 1985-1999 (Box 162, Folder 6-12, Box 163, Folder 1-5, Box 199, Folder 6, Box 246, Box 249, Folder 250, Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 21)
    1985-1993; 1994 (except Sept); 1995-1997; Mar-Dec 1998; Feb-Nov 1999
  - Irish America, 2000-2009 (Box 164, Folder 1-5, Folder 16-17, Box 199, Folder 6, Box 200, Box 1-4, Box 246, Folder 2-5, Box 248, Folder 3, Folder 250, Folder 6-8)
    Jan 2000-Mar 2000; Nov 2000; Jan-Nov 2001; Dec-Jan 2002; Feb-Nov 2002; Jan-Nov 2003; Jan-Sept 2004; Jan-Nov 2005; Jan-May 2006; 2007 (except Feb-Mar); 2008 (except April-May); 2009 (except Dec)
  - Irish America, 2010-2019 (Box 164, Folder 5A, Box 200, Folder 4-5, Box 201, Box 239, Folder 2, Box 246, Folder 5-9, Box 247, Folder 1-5, Box 248, Folder 3-7)
    Feb/Mar 2010; Apr/May 2010; Jun/July 2010; Aug/Sept 2010; Oct/Nov, 2010; Dec 2010/Jan 2011; 2011 (all issues); Dec 2011/Jan 2012; Aug/Sept 2012; Dec 2012/Jan 2013; Feb/Mar 2013; Apr/May 2013; Jun/July 2013; Oct/Nov 2013; Dec 2013/Jan 2014; Apr/May 2014; Jun/Jul 2014; Aug/Sept 2014; Oct/Nov 2014; Aug/Sept 2015; Oct/Nov 2015; Feb/Mar 2016; Apr/May 2016; Feb/Mar 2017; Fe/Mar 2016; Jun/Jul 2016; Apr/May 2017; Jun/Jul 2018; Sept/Oct 2018; Nov/Dec 2018; Jan/Feb 2019; Mar/Apr 2019; May/Jun 2019
  - Irish America, 2023 (Box 247, Folder 6)
    Fall 2023
  - Irish America, 2024 (Box 247, Folder 7)
    Winter 2024
  - The Irish American Democrat, 2012, 2016 (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - Irish American Post Magazine, 1997; cuid14866 (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - Irish American Voice, 1984-1987; cuid14867 (Box 164, Folder 7-10)
  - Irish Arts Center -- IAC | NYC, 2017-2019 (Box 247, Folder 8)
    Fall 2017; Fall/Spring 2018; Fall 2019
  - Irish Connections, 2001-2002, 2004, 2006, 2011, 2013; cuid14919 (Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 21, Box 201, Folder 4-5, Box 239, Folder 3, Box 247, Folder 11)
  - Irish Dancer, 1998; cuid14872 (Box 164, Folder 12)
  - IE: A Supplement to the Irish Echo, 1996-1998; cuid14873 (Box 164, Folder 13)
  - Irish Emigrant, 1997-2000 (Box 201, Folder 6)
  - Irish at Home and Abroad, 1993-1995; cuid14871 (Box 164, Folder 11)
  - Irish Life, 1989 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - Irish People (Chicago) Vol. 1, nos. 5-6, 8-12; Vol 2. nos. 5,9,11; Vol 3. no. 1 (also available on microfilm in Tamiment), Oct 1923-Jan 1933 with gaps; cuid14874 (Box 164, Folder 14)
  - The Irish Republican Guard: Issues 3-5, 2009; cuid14875 (Box 166, Folder 17)
  - The Irish Review, 1934 (Box 247, Folder 10)
  - The Irish Review, 1937; cuid14920 (Box Shared Tamiment 018, Folder 21)
  - Irish Voice Magazine, 1954; cuid14876 (Box 164, Folder 15)
  - Irish Volunteer, 1991, 2000; cuid14877 (Box 164, Folder 16)
  - Keltoi: A Pan-Celtic Review, 1986-1987, 1990; cuid14878 (Box 164, Folder 17)
  - Lies of Our Times: British Terror in Northern Ireland, Oct 1990; cuid14879 (Box 164, Folder 18)
  - Nation, The (Ho Ho Kus, NJ), 1985-1995; cuid14880 (Box 164, Folder 19-20, Box 165, Folder 1-5)
  - Nua Eabhrac, 1981-1981; cuid14887 (Box 165, Folder 6)
  - Pioneer, 1978-1986 (Box 202, Folder 1-2)
  - The Recorder: Bulletin of the American Irish Historical Society. (New York), 1926, 1932-1970, 1972-1982, 1985-2002, 2004, 2006-2010; cuid14888 (Box 167, Box 202, Folder 3-4, Box 203, Folder 1-7, Box 204, Folder 1-5, Box 205, Box 206, Folder 1-4, Box 207, Folder 1-3, Box Shared Tamiment 188, Folder 8-9, Box Shared Tamiment 189, Box 248, Folder 1)
    Scope and Content Note
    Holdings: 1926, Vol. 15; 1932, Vol. 5, no. 5; 1933, Vol. 6, nos. 2-4; 1934, Vol. 7, nos. 1-3; 1935, Vol. 8, no. 1; 1936, Vol. 9, nos. 1-4; 1939, Vol. 10, no. 1-2, 6; 1950, Vol. 12, no. 1; 1951, Vol. 13, no. 1; 1952, Vol. 14; 1953, Vol. 15; 1954, Vol. 16; 1955, Dec. 1962, Vol. 25; Vol. 16; 1963, Vol. 24; 1964, Vol. 26; 1965; Feb 1965, Vol. 27; Vol. 28; 1966, Vol. 29; 1967, Vol. 30; 1968, Vol. 31; Dec. 1969, Vol. 32; 1970, Vol. 33; 1973, Vol. 34; 1974, Vol. 35; 1975, Vol. 36; 1976, Vol. 37; 1977, Vol 38; 1978, Vol. 39; 1979, Vol. 40; 1980, Vol. 41; 1981, Vol. 42; 1982, Vol. 43; Winter 1985, Vol. 1, no. 1; Winter 1986, Vol. 2, no. 1; Summer 1987, Vol. 2, no.2; Winter 1988, Vol. 3, no. 1; Summer 1989, Vol. 3, no.1; Winter 1989, Vol. 3, no. 2; Supplement to 1988 "In Memoriam Darcy O'Brien;" List of Publications, 1898-1943 [from 1952 on it looks like only one bulletin was published per annum]; Summer 1990, Vol. 3, no. 3; Summer 1991, Vol. 5, no. 4; Winter 1991, Vol. 5, no. 2; Summer 1992, Vol. 6, no. 1; Fall 1993, Vol. 6, no. 2; Summer 1994, Vol. 7, no. 1; Fall 1994, Vol. 7, no. 2; Spring 1995, Vol. 8, no. 1; Fall 1995, Vol. 8, no. 2; Spring 1996, Vol. 9, no. 1; Fall 1996, Vol. 9, no. 2; Spring 1998, Vol. 11, no. 1; Fall 1998, Vol. 11, no. 2; Spring 1999, Vol. 12, no. 1; Fall 1999, Vol. 12, no. 2; Spring 2000, Vol. 13, no. 1; Fall 200, Vol. 13, no. 2; Summer 2001, Vol. 14, no. 1; Fall 2001, Vol. 14, no. 2; Spring 2002, Vol. 15, no. 1; Fall 2002, Fall 2004, Vol 17, no. 2; Vol. 15, no. 2; Summer 2006, Vol. 19, no. 1; Summer 2007, Vol. 19, no. 2 and Vol. 20, no. 1; Spring/Fall 2008, Vol. 20, no. 2 and Vol. 21, no. 1; Spring/Fall 2009, Vol. 21, no. 2 and Vol. 22, no. 1; Fall 2010, Vol. 22, no. 2
  - Republican Bulletin / Iris na Poblachta (Dublin) Vol. 1, nos. 1-3, 1987; cuid14889 (Box 165, Folder 7)
  - Saoirse': Irish Freedom, 1987-1997; cuid14890 (Box 165, Folder 8)
  - Shamrock Leaf, 1990-1996; cuid14891 (Box 165, Folder 9)
  - Shanachie, The, 1990-2000; cuid14892 (Box 165, Folder 10)
  - Spirit of Freedom, 1986-1989; cuid14893 (Box 165, Folder 11-13)
  - University College Dublin Alumni Newsletter, Jun 1989-Jan 1993; cuid14896 (Box 165, Folder 14)
  - University College Dublin Alumni Magazine, 1993-2000; cuid14897 (Box 165, Folder 15-16)
  - World of Hibernia, 1995-2001; cuid14899 (Box 165, Folder 17-20, Box 166, Folder 1-9)